on the 2012 London Olympics and welcome
to the final of the women's 10 metre
platform we had a rather edgy prelims
slightly better semi-final earlier today
and hopefully we will be on course for
an exemplary 10 meter final tonight
Yulia go got Chuck just getting in in
12th place all of these dives including
this lady in particular looking to do a
great deal better tonight bronze
medalist from last year at - Paolo
Sanchez Espinosa Sanchez she's built on
the screen no me bat key of Italy will
be after her and who you Dan may be
somewhat surprised see a Chinese diver
so far down the pecking order hasn't
really gone into gear either in the
prelims on the semi swishes in there as
indeed is Roslin finial a much better
semi-final and she did preliminary
Christians Joe has had a low degree of
difficulty in her program
let's work to her benefit doesn't always
go for the big numbers make sure she has
been consistent as has yulia coulton
over russia now on to the big hitters
right at the top of the pile and after
both the prelims and the semi-final and
to the bank now that's a word the to
America to Australians I should say
together and they will be following one
another in the competition tonight very
impressive was this young lady 16 years
of age on to the second ranked after the
semi-final making bent feet oh but you
have to say head and shoulders and
virtually all of a torso ahead of
everybody else on the basis of what we
saw this morning and indeed last night
in the preliminaries is the top ranked
of the Chinese defending champion chain
rule in well we're just about ready to
go but of course the competition cannot
start we can't get this party started
without one very special addition to the
guest list
Leon Taylor good evening sir thank you
Bob
well there there it is there is the
10-meter platform towering above all the
other diving boards very very close to
this ceiling and we have finally the
finalists here now it's been well
fair-to-middling I would say so far
generally speaking the polymer EES were
full of mishaps and mix ups and the semi
finals weren't actually much better so
we finally got there we have 12 divers
each of the divers will perform five
optional dives so these are the most
difficult dives that these girls can
perform the total from each dive is
obviously added to the next into the
next so the sequence if score decides
the places and as Bob's already
mentioned there is one person who is a
cut above that is the Beijing Olympic
champion at only 15 years old now she's
the grand old age of 19 and she is well
miles in front like she already
qualified for the final after round four
she did not even need to perform her
last dive that is how good this young
lady is then there's you you Dan now she
is suffering I'm not sure whether she's
injured no one seems to know but she is
off her game heading into their hot tub
there
the divers tend to pop in and out of
that just to keep the muscles warm in
between dives obviously they dive in a
sequence in an order and that water
stays the same throughout those handling
I'm think that she could be on four
medal the 19-year old for Malaysia nice
outfit she's been looking really solid
and she looks really relaxed there's the
coaching Corral keep them all penned in
there as if they were sheep in their
shoes she's 16 from Australia now if I
was allowed to bet I'd be betting on
this young lady for a medal
she is well come from strength to
strength to strength there's Paul
Espinoza way off the pace in the prelims
and semi now can she ride that Mexican
high that they've been on in the diving
pool no question about the young
Australians going back to her
on round four dive I think on both
occasions she's not dropped it exactly
but she hasn't done very well so 1 2 3 &
5 look great it's round 4 that could do
for her
yep what he said yeah well it could go
either way he couldn't it we will tee
that one up when it comes the first time
we're just making her way up to the
10-meter board there 5 dives they all go
in different directions five different
dives from the six available groups of
dive from the platform so that's
forwards and backwards inwards which is
where you stand backwards and spin
forwards towards the diving board the
reverse which is where you stand
forwards and jump away spinning
backwards towards the diving board and
the twist which is where you rotate
longitudinally as well and also the arm
stand group so five dives out of those
six groups so you'll see lots of
different dives at different times but
and we can explain a little more as we
go along
and the final gets underway well I can't
explain for you in terms of the dives in
the first round you will see nine out of
the 12 divers go for a Ford three and a
half with difficulty of 3.0 and the pike
position the first five and nine out of
twelve will do this particular dive
including the opening diver julia row up
Chuck
of Ukraine
get in this contest underway it's more
the audience is filling up as we speak
very busy Olympic Park I'm sure most of
the seats will be taken so first diver
the pike shape they're letting her down
a little bit she needs to be tighter in
a Pike shape so the chest should be flat
on the legs she chooses not to hold
around the back of the thighs and Link
you know hand to elbow which is what a
lot of the divers do it's a peculiar
technique she does a good job though
well I see opening gambit from her
seventeen point five zero four product
chuck of ukraine as i mentioned you'll
see that dive performed pretty much by
all of the divers in the first round all
I would say about this lady and so she
gets going is Paolo Espinosa Sanchez of
Mexico well that's much better than the
prelims much better than the semi-final
has Paola finally woken up whatever
she's had to do this afternoon but she
needs to refocus it all looks good so
far fantastic aerial work as always just
tipping over a vertical but that should
sneak a few seven and a half's and eight
it looks like a better opening dive on
the Mexican mm which way is it going to
go for this evening I was feeling
personally responsible for
underperforming both in the prelims out
of a semi so I'm just keeping my
distance and keep my counsel on what she
does here seventy point five zero says
she matches prog optic with the same
dive and he comes near me bat key of
Italy
likewise well that's the best one so far
that's the best one out of three we can
definitely compare like for like so
approaching the end of the diving board
with speed you need to turn that forward
momentum into upward momentum driving
those hips up and over squeezing into
that Pike shape that's a really good
Pike shape there was no daylight in
between the chest and the thighs look at
that beautiful dive from the Italian the
other two dives got 70.5 zero back he is
looking for a bigger score than that
same tariff different score though
seventy six point five zero remember the
Mark's with the lines through them do
not count may point fives across the
board do multiplied by the degree of
difficulty that's how you arrive at her
starting figure her first round score of
seventy six point five zero his who well
there is something wrong with this young
lady now I you know that the Chinese
keep their cards close to their chest so
no one knows whether she's injured ill
or but there's definitely something
amiss she is world silver medalist from
last year
yes she's only sixteen years old but she
was silver medalist behind the Olympic
champion last year and she is all over
the shop again so this means the medals
are wide open if you done continues to
dive like this she will be miles off the
pace this is interesting yeah she's only
had really one dive of caliber equality
this morning and likewise last night and
coach just giving her stare a few
well-chosen words by the looks of things
as we move on to Rosaline Finney on our
candidate same dive once again ranked
eighth in the semi final you see if she
can match the net she looked a little
tired this morning and I'm not surprised
these girls finished late last night in
the polymer region had to get up early
this morning to dive in the semi-finals
Roslyn looked a little bit off her game
and this looks a better effort for her
it's only gonna get sevens throwing up a
little bit too much splash squeezing
into the pike shape it seems to be
moving a head to the side there for some
reason but peculiar but she ended up on
her head which is where she wanted to be
now remind of course the judges do not
see the replay that you see we see
several times from different angles they
only get one look at it in real time so
and there's still nuances that early on
might point out probably not apparent
and not obvious to the judges in their
position down below
63 for filly on different diving kristen
stewart
2.8 in woods two and a half somersault
solo tariff needs to be good
well that's the best one she's done out
the three so prelims it was awful the
semi-final she stepped up and she
started with a weakness tied to put an
eighth degree of difficulty now we've
seen some girls hit their feet on this
story not too far away from the platform
it's very difficult to jump far enough
away and still complete the rotations
she's probably gonna get sevens on that
but because of the low degree of
difficulty it struggled to get over 60
points yeah just struggling past the 60
barrier 60 points to 0 for Christine
step just rushed back to turn the gas
off now into yulia coulton over and
there is only one arm stand in the first
round semi that can beat a regular pace
for a change crowd ooh haven't seen this
before doing an re already on the arm
stand forward double somersault one
twist
she started beautifully in the
semi-final with this dive that one there
she's just overcooked it giving it a
little bit too much on the start meant
that it was very difficult to control
with that much rotation so bending at
the arms flicking off very much like a
gymnastics vault wrapping into the twist
there we are just over rotating as she
goes in there maybe seven and a half on
that it's a real shame because it's very
confident to open with the arm stands
that takes some nerves to no control of
your nerves I should say take some nerve
well seventy two point eight five is
what she has accrued from that everybody
else who costing an arm stand most of
them and little later on pretty much all
in the third round so she opens her
program with an arm stand which
currently puts her in second place
behind the Italian bat key was the
Malaysian pang back we go to the for
three and a half again with Pike whoa is
she feeling the pressure she's been
performing very well and she's got
herself in the business end of the field
through her performance in the
semi-final only 19 years old really like
a diving superb flexibility look at that
her toes is that
nose is almost touching her ankles her
flexibility is that good however she's
let the dive go over which means it's
your struggle to get more than six is
six and a half on that and she's off the
pace start that she had in either the
prelims all the semis little bit of
reparation work already to be done the
four and a pang of Malaysia on to the
two Australians now again a four three
and a half for the slightly older of the
two Aussies Melissa would more very
smooth beautiful entry what the judges
are looking for is a vertical entry with
absolutely no splash in Melissa rube
who is bang on the money with that when
her opening dive you've seen this before
lots of the girls opening with this one
seems to be a very popular choice it's
3.0 she's going to get eight in the
house for sure on that one just what the
judges are looking for she's up the game
she's moved the bar upwards Wow
78 and disappeared without a trace into
the water that's what you want to see
and that's what she wanted to do and she
has achieved that with great alacrity
Melissa woo good start for her 78 puts
her into a lead coach still not happy
they never are from the 20 year old
Australian to the 16 year old Australian
Brittany Broman 2.7 low degree of
difficulty to start off with it's a
reverse two and a half somersaults
or she's played just a little bit safe
what a shame because this was an
absolute corker in the semi-finals
it had nines written all over it this
one all the way until the water and she
just keeps her chin in a little bit she
didn't look back enough in order to get
it right into the vertical position we
all just needed to pull back a little
bit she's gonna get seven and a half but
what a shame because wow she would it
needed nines it's a low degree of
difficulty this young lady's got some
work to do she's going to live up to the
well my prediction of a medal for her
come on yeah I put the mouth on poor
Mexican likewise fear you with the
Australian it would seem because that's
not the best dive by quite some way that
bro Boone has done over the last two
days on to the second half of the
Canadians
here's Megan Murphy to--again the for
three and a half oh here we go
I wondered when we would see the first
mistake archer they're showing with his
body language that that was very poor
wow I didn't expect to see a mistake of
that magnitude from this young lady
especially she's been one of the more
consistent can competitors through the
prelims and a semi which was a well
actually well what a shame not to splash
over onto her back low marks incoming
now what a shame especially as it looks
like even early stages a silver and a
bronze might be up for grabs today and
5.5 s just will not cut it
if you're looking to get into second or
third place first place surely is
secured before we even start by a chin
well that's how you should do it that's
definitely worth eight and a half and
nines superb technically very very good
pops up into that Pike shape no daylight
in-between the chest in the air at chest
and the thighs drills the entry
superb and away she goes
well the Crowley getting excited now why
are they getting excited well because
there's a 10 on the scoreboard sadly as
in previous competition it doesn't count
was it worth the 10 but a 9.5 s most
certainly do and eighty five point five
zero she's already proving she's in a
class of her own but just look at the
gap after round one she's already got a
gap of seven points over Melissa will in
second naomi backe and third yulia
coulton over in for power Espinoza
Sanchez much better start from her this
time round those are the ones in early
stages pushing for the medals I wasn't
leaving Philly are not too far away but
Megan Ben feet oak at the bottom of the
pile along with Lu you Dan mmm in 11th
place with a Chinese now coach made it
very clear exactly what she thought of
that dive she's gone away with a flea in
the rear only for round number two which
starts now
second round of the women's 10-meter
platform final already developing into a
very interesting contest not so much for
the main place but for the silver and
the bronze and there are plenty in
competition for that including you only
a pro cop shook up to three point two on
the degree of difficulty for her in with
three and a half somersaults equal fifth
after first round war she sneaks that
one in G us beautifully Wow an okay
start backed up with her one of the
highest degrees of difficulty in in with
three and a half that sees the safe
distance from the diving board some of
the girls have been coming in a little
bit too close for comfort
I think that's gonna just get over 70
points and she certainly laid a marker
down let's see what happens after this
is
7.5 for 72 complete and what's unique it
in is in the Leon Taylor drinking game
but it should be because while beginning
rather Brahms and this by the end of the
evening now on to power Espinoza Sanchez
of Mexico back three and a half summer
sports with tuck three point three the
degree of difficulty for the Mexican War
she's more on her game but still you
know I think that says it all that's
actually the Italian coach is kind of
gone well it's okay but we expect to see
more from this accomplished diver
she's got medals from everywhere already
Olympic medalist here silver medal in
the 10-meter synchro and that is good
but I was expecting to see nines at her
very best in or get seven seven point
five s going over a vertical if she goes
in the divers holding they could see
their heavy the wrists taped to help
with the impact just see the feet coming
towards us there and there's the wave
catch a wave and she did didn't really
want to produce that but seventy four
point two five is good enough to put her
into first place marginally at this
stage good start from there me backe
she's gone from a three point zero down
to a two point nine in round two Hingham
two back two and a half somersaults in
the pike position it's probably her
weakest dive in the program leaning away
from the diving board a little bit too
far there which means it's very
difficult to control the dive and
therefore when you're looking for that
precise entry vertical entry
gerrae sometimes get some drift which is
what happened there over as she goes in
throwing up a little bit of splash just
see the body tension required to hold
yourself when you're hurtling towards
the water incredible impact speeds she
holds on to it there see what the judges
think when they think seven point five
across the board in terms of marks
account sixty five point two five
remember it is a degree of difficulty
after those marks have been added up and
then multiplied gives you sixty five
point
two-five now who you dan mystery
regarding here at the moment why is she
diving so poorly was that just a blip or
not oh good night you cannot make
glaring errors like that and expect to
feature on the podium now it's wide open
for the rest of the ladies wow this is
really interesting she's a little tight
to the platform there Wow aerial work is
good she just doesn't seem to know where
she is I wonder if it'll come out after
the contest if there was anything wrong
with her from an illness point of view
or an injury because she is way off her
games like the coach doesn't want to
talk to her so wait a minute consolation
there and just get along with it and
forty three point two zero how do you
know what she said what do you speak no
I'm just looking at body language
interpretation Thank You neon Rosalie
and filly on now backward three and a
half somersaults tuck 3.30 there you go
she saved the best until the final this
young lady was way off the pace in the
prelims and in the semi-final hence her
early start position in this final this
is the dive that was giving her
difficulty she's woken up and she saved
her best back three and a half until now
this is big because you can't see where
you're going you're spinning backwards
you can only see where you've been you
have to point your feet up which he does
well spot on good work yep nods to the
coach and she can go into the punch ball
very happy that she's picked up seventy
five point nine zero that lifts up to
fourth place not that far behind the
main movers and shakers Christine step
of Germany moved up from the ranks of
the upper twos to the early threes six
six three point two try six point two
three point two back two and a half
somersaults well she's renowned for her
very clean entries what you're looking
for is a splash less entry
what Stewart is famed for a takeoff sir
very average indeed so she's quite weak
not as very dynamic or strong as some of
the other girls but she can certainly
get her dives in with hardly a riffle of
splash and that will probably get seven
and a half maybe an eighth the judges
marks and yep they're going with you on
that they're going with the eights and
giving her a total accumulative score of
seventy six point eight zero and again
she's bunching up in a quite a large
pack of seven marks surrounding five
divers at this stage that's how tight
this competition is yulia colton over
fourth after round one
just going a little bit loose in a lower
back if she went in her takeoff is a
little bit weak which means the dive is
always going to finish very very low to
the water which means that you need to
do a well a pretty good job of getting
out of it very very quickly and trying
to hide that from the judges just see
they're just turning into a bit of a
banana woman as she goes in see on the
super slow-motion arching through the
lower back yeah just needed a little bit
more speed to that rotation in order to
give herself a fraction more time it's
okay but needed to be better yeah okay
prolly won't quite make it done in a
final for her she's a bit better than
that needs more consistency than that
and sixty 1.05 for Carlton over means
that she's back in sixth place
Angela pang of Malaysia two point nine
back two and a half seven sorts oh it's
an absolute corker
shaky first round dive there we go her
teammates shouting and screaming and so
would I be beautiful take off such so
strong
fantastic look how she glides out with
her feet pointing down of the water and
absolutely buries the entry it's only
two point nine but when you score nines
on it like she will do here keeps you in
the mix good work yeah what a shame she
started with a 58.5 or or she'd be right
up there as an issues not too far adrift
she's made up some ground with that
seventy eight point three zero and she
is up to sixth but today is six up to
one separated by eight points the moment
early stage of course I'm here out to to
another of those armed stands there are
three point two variety and a three
point three variety and there will be a
three point one as well as the later on
but the most popular choice of the three
point two which this is stand back
double somersault one and a half twist
four whoo it's important that you show a
steady arm balance to the judges before
you go and Melissa manage that and then
this is where the hard work starts flick
the legs lift up the shoulders into the
twist and then finish that dive off
that's consistent sevens on this seven
and a half maybe to go with her first
round dive which is a good score 78 I
think first round 72 that's good yeah
into the lead she goes it's a lead of
about six points she is setting the mark
for everybody else to follow including
her Australian teammate that's Brittany
Broman 16 years of age you know with
three and a half somersaults 3.2 in the
tuck position for Brittany Broman
all right tremendous that should get
nines and 9.5 Wow there you go she knows
it's such a good feeling when you get a
dive like this that drills into the
water it's okay it's a safe distance and
this feeling when you bury a dive like
that it's almost like you're being
teleported some arouses extraordinary
noise in the ears of buzz through the
body into the water
big score 83 yeah very big scoring Dean
again it just ashamed that her first I
was not that accurate and not executed
to the fall and to the max because she
would be very much at the top as it
issues third that 83 point to zero now
Megan Vinh feto has some ground to make
up already it's not irretrievable three
point three back three and a half again
tuck position and they can find yourself
in the other custom position 12 well
that's gonna help that certainly is
gonna help such a shame when you blow
your opening dive when you lead yourself
with so much to do but he's obviously
left that dive where it is there's
nothing else you can do but focus on the
next one and that is a corker to come
back with wow we're finally seeing some
high quality dives from the ladies well
we are but from her point of view she
will look up at the scoreboard a moment
and see the classification after round 2
and she will know that she hasn't
actually made up a lot of ground at all
in terms of places when she's gone from
12 to 10 and you imagine this lady will
have number one besides her name and she
has done all the way through the
preliminaries and semi finals just
oozing confidence and hardly putting a
foot wrong so far in with three and a
half somersaults for the run away number
one Chinese at the moment formed in the
Tuck position here comes chain Ruolin
World and Olympic champion oh it's
fabulous
not worth attend maybe nines on that the
only thing incorrect or the only thing
wrong with that dive was there was a
little bit of splash thrown up
technically perfect jumps up over the
diving board squeezing into a perfect
tuck shape kick site through a pike
position very very well executed they'll
get over 80 points just showing her
class here look at the ankle snap
they're droplets of water tape on the
lower back to support an injury she has
but wow she does not look as though
she's going to get caught
follows up an 85.5 with an 84.8
and already a massive chasm between one
and the rest already a lead of 20 points
really yes 20 points between the Chinese
and the rest and here comes the
standings aren't around to 170 already
accrued for Chen rule in their Melissa
whoop and Paulo Espinoza Sanchez in
third which near Obon not far away or
indeed Illya her gotcha
I was trying to cast a few adrift at the
bottom a little hoot look who is at the
bottom who is at the bottom who's at the
bottom very interesting first two rounds
just to confirm how the judging works
there are seven judges each of the
judges mark out of ten the two highest
and two lowest marks are discounted to
leave the three remaining marks those
are the three without the lines through
those three marks are then added
together multiplied by 2 by of the
degree of difficulty to give the total
for that particular dive round 3
first diver here properly 2.9 back two
and a half summer sorts with pike it's
good she is having a consistent
performance 2.9 derivative got nice some
of the girls going for the backward
three and a half this young lady was
slightly easier back with two and a half
pipes and it's very good she just let
the legs drop there and arches into a
lower back doesn't seem to affect the
end she struggled to get more than seven
and a half so is it just drifts over a
vertical look at the tension on the
audience faces when the divers are there
going through the air having friends
family and acquaintances through agony
all of them and sixty five point two
five four broke up Chuck and she becomes
the first diver to go through the 200
barrier no foul up Espinoza Sanchez
reversed three and a half somersaults
with tuck she's worked her way up to
number three after round number two
oh it's good she's just a little bit
over throwing the splash up towards a
dime but she's the only female
performing this dive the men all do this
dive you need to be incredibly strong
incredibly dynamic to perform the
reverse three and a half and she does it
almost effortlessly but just overcooked
it over a vertical well I don't know six
is maybe but I'm impressed with the dive
that it's so difficult but not so
impressed with the execution or maybe
she's thinking that wasn't really part
of the plan and certainly wasn't really
a dive perhaps I should be included in
my program but it's priam she will have
done time and time again feels
comfortable enough with it but not feel
that comfortable with a score of sixty
one point zero five which temporarily at
least puts it into second place now and
they owe me back key three point two
back two and a half somersaults one and
a half twists formed in the pike
position that straight up-and-down
margin me short as she went into the
water quite complex lots of the girls
will be finishing on this dive three
point two degree of difficulty so the
potential is you can score very well
owner indeed over seventy points would
be a good score over 80 points should be
even better I think this will get early
70s it does 72 for Naomi backe seven
point five so we'll count the other
scores do not tell me to is the total
score for the Hungarian born Italian now
who you Dan twelfth place after round
two obviously out of sorts for reasons
that we don't really know I would back
double somersaults and this you got
three point to attach to it
well that's more like it she was
straight up and down vertical entry
throwing up a little bit of splash she
doesn't have any tape on her nothing on
the wrist nothing on the ankles lots of
the divers adding support to some of the
joints with tape whoo you Dan that's
much more like it but she's left herself
way too much to do that's a good shot
isn't it close up on the face popping up
into that twist technically very very
good indeed little bit of splash being
thrown up other than that it's a good
dive one of the few we've seen from this
young lady yeah she left it as Leo was
saying way too late though
mathematically everybody else would have
to go sideways and not complete their
dives for her to be in with a chance
it's just too much of a hill to climb
now for her Roslyn filly on in seventh
after round two in word three and a half
somersaults with tuck seen it before
here it is again worth three point two
in terms of degree of difficulty well a
little bit looser she went in not quite
holding the tension coaches obviously
clapping anyway just there we go arching
in the lower back not quite holding the
tension takeoff is good a little bit low
on the water so it needed to be sharp
out they can see just a little bit of
you know wavering in the body tension
throwing up that splash probably gets
Evans not quite as good as her previous
divers got 70
yeah doesn't match the seventy five
point nine zero she got in round two
sixty seven point two zero and it's
waiting again for anybody other than
general int to take this competition by
the scruff of the neck and say I want a
medal
there's nobody yet from her it's really
shown their full range top competitive
instincts they all stand back double
somersault well and a half twists fresh
dirt overcooked it too much on the start
so it's very important that you pop up
into this dive if you lean too far you
get too much whip and that causes
increased rotation which is exactly what
story does here and she just can't stop
it and over she goes so move slightly
down the field a little bit further away
from standing on the podium yeah well
nothing you can do about it now four
dimes have gone over 200 she has not as
yet and you've got to be up there to be
in the medal contention and she is fifth
currently few divers still go including
Yulia
Carlton over 3.0 back yeah opening dive
of the same degree of difficulty for
three and a half no I really like that
their work is superb she spins really
fast rotation giving her plenty of time
to line up she does let the dive go over
a vertical only marginally so this could
get ate slightly poor second round dive
has left her a little bit off the pace
only tenth after round two she will move
up after that good third round effort
there we go feeling that my calculator
might be blowing steam out by the end of
this evening it's gonna be an awful lot
of numbers to crunch at the end of this
competition because they are so so tight
for the minor medals if we ignore the
victor and gold medal ekta get everybody
else to stand a bunch up in that two to
eight position
and in a pang ix of the moment 3.2
degree of difficulty on this arm stand
back double somersault one and half
twists she's done exactly the same as
Christine she has gone after the dive a
little bit too aggressively and
therefore she's yeah she knows you can
tell by a body language here we go just
a little bit too aggressive and then
when she be pikes can't stop it from
going over you can see the splash moving
away from the diving board six and a
half's sevens at best moving further
away from the podium dive after dive
star with a 58 and it with a 64 this
time on a three point two dives she
would be lucky for upper 70s so probably
a tariff -15 on that means that she's
not really pushing no she's hitting very
similar figures to her right now
Melissa woo back three and a half
somersault with tuck is this the dive
that might cause us some problems she's
been pretty impeccable today three point
three degree of difficulty biggest one
that she does
oh you caught it Bob
I was doing my hand signal with a
shaking hand which means this is the
bogey dive which way is it going to go
and the answer to that is short short a
vertical on the entry just running out
of room she drifts back a little bit too
far kicks out a fraction too early lands
short of vertical five and a half sand
60s and that puts the cat amongst the
pigeons and everyone is bunched up
apart from a mule in everyone's bunched
up so no one watch so silver or bronze
looks like now does brittany broman want
to break out of the pack and show her
mettle 16 years of age show that she's a
very mature 16 year old has not phased
by anything here this will be a real
test for her though again it's the 3.2
armstand 3.3 coming later but this is a
3.2 version of it
stand back so Marcella sorts
time of the season of course that could
double somersault oh yes oh yes wow that
is bang on the money it doesn't get
better than that that entry is just well
there I say it's near-perfect
as it needs to be if anything she could
do with being a little bit tighter in
the air but lies a splash this entry
really really good judges were pretty
penalized because she was losing your
feet and legs a little bit in the air
they have but look at that eight point
five two nine 83 hello Australian eight
point five and nine makes your
catchphrase s alright it's a very good
die for the second Australian who's
becoming very much the first Australian
here as bromine goes into a 14-point
lead obviously won't hang around for too
long
saying Canadian will be followed very
shortly by the Chinese but he comes bent
feet OHS in with three and a half which
is 11th after round two so these dives
don't have to be absolutely impeccable
as she stands any chance of making a
challenge
nope she's got it on her head she is the
right way up Justin shot there that's a
shammy the divers use that to dry off
the legs so they can grip onto the shins
here as Megan's demonstrating if your
hands are wet and Chin's are wet you can
slip out and that isn't very good at all
also for drying themselves off and keep
him warm it's his good but she's left
herself way too much to do what an
absolute shame yep not her day 72 is an
okay mark but it's not good enough what
she needs at this stage
appreciating talent there's a lot of
Chinese supporters in the crowd I think
everybody just knows how good this young
lady is the big world champion 19 years
of age and out general in I'm stand back
double somersault again 3.2 already with
a 20-point lead and adding to that lead
dive after dive so consistent plenty of
Chinese support here and we are seeing a
master at work
here she is one and a half twist double
somersault drilling the entry just a
little bit too much glass for more than
a nine but three point two nines across
the board big score increased lead you
hear her 29 points now 20 up to 29 and
my new details maybe she's doing wrong
good for the majority of the time for
most of the dives it wasn't a great deal
you can fought it by 256 29 point lead
for general in Brittany browbone into
second 14-point lead for her preferred
over back heat and they're queuing up
behind for a got Chuck Philly on and Wu
on that page maybe over 200 probably
still just about then
Colton over Sanchez bent feet oh and
Pangu you damn it down if you do get
down if you don't so forth to 11th there
is what seven or eight points bunched up
nice to see bourbon in second place my
tip round for opening divert you earlier
for a got Chuck and gums the arm back
trip with summer sorts talking about the
three-point twos first time we get to
see the three point three in this
competition so the town for a bit higher
the risk a bit higher - oh she's smoked
it and some of the divers say when you
get the water get into the water without
any splash there's many different
terminologies use just pick one at the
archives there and she smoked it
Wow three point three high-risk high
degree of difficulty arm stand back
triple somersault in the tuck position
beautiful for fine die from the
Ukrainian keep himself in contention
your distance from the board good marks
across the Lord eight eight and eight
three point three degree of difficulty
when he add it all up comes to seventy
nine point two zero and she has put
herself in a good position for a medal
I'm currently in first place
Paulo Espinosa Sanchez of Mexico in with
three and a half we're tuck
or that's her best I've so fast she just
has his tendency to go in with a slight
back arch which gives the impression
she's much further over a vertical than
she actually is
that's so best dive so far you can't
fault this lady's takeoffs they are spot
on the entry into the water and letting
it down a yet again it's going to be her
high-scoring dive and get eight eight
point five well maybe she'd be putting
himself back in contention one dive to
go 18 points is good 80 points is very
good but is it enough not to take the
lead it's not because Brooke got Chuck
has got that by just over a mark and
that's how tight this competition really
is near me back key it's currently in
third place in with three and a half for
her three point two with tuck 80-85 she
goes flying back up the standings again
all feeling the pressure third after the
third round may be surprised to see
yourself so far up the field and this is
one of her most difficult dives safe
dishes from the diving board just
hanging on to a tuck shape a little bit
too long just a fraction over rotating
it'll only get I don't think it will get
17 so shuffling the pack once again yeah
it's almost kind of right will you have
a go now I'm quite happy to sit back and
watch you do something good or bad or
indifferent sixty eight point eight zero
four back eek and she goes well she's at
third now but she won't be staying there
for a long who you're damn sorry first
she's just so far off a game today back
three and a half with tuck go there you
go there is the burst of brilliance
it's young 16 year old silver medalist
from there we are the coaches a big
beaming smile she knows what she could
do this girl dives all day every day at
such a standard and this is a standard
that I'm accustomed to commentating on
from this superb talent from China but
she is messed up her first two dives so
considerably that even though this is
going to score poor nearly 90 points I
would imagine she will still only be
creeping up the field at best Wow look
at that
89 highs Markov the competition with
those nines multiplied by three point
three and she has moved up a few places
but she is still 23 points behind Pro
got chucked and 22 behind Sanchez and
that's gonna be a lot more ground to
make up three point three not really
helping in terms of I was in Philly all
getting in an upright position there arm
stand back triple somersault three point
three we're tuck oh it's good couldn't
quite hold the splash going really
strong takeoff she heals almost touch
the back of her legs as she bends in
fact they do lower back in fact flicks
in holding a little bit high on her
knees there
yes letting the dive go marginally over
so it's three point three so get a good
score it'll get over 70 points and if
she was more that might you did even
more pleased with that throwing up too
much splash seventy two point six zero
for the time being she moves up into
fourth mind bro got Chuck Sanchez and
backe has only eight points behind the
current leader that's makeable Kristine
step of Germany myself at the wrong end
of the table in 11th and this is a low
tariff dive which may not help her in
her reparation back two and a half whoa
what a dive that's exactly what you did
in the semi-finals very experienced and
this is exactly how you finish off a
dive a little bit low height wise
that's why she goes for the slightly
easier backward moving once she gets in
the water there with hardly a ripple of
splash little bit arched through the
lower back here as she pulls it round
but you can't fault that entry only
behind there she comes and here come the
mark seventy-three point nine five I
could tell you that's yulia coulton over
of russia up next eight point five s
across the board and she will go into
the lead which it obviously is second
place in terms of this competition with
the and one chinese dominating but she
can go right up to second overall if she
gets this three point two right oh and
she does she gets hit bang on the money
well predicted Bob I was watching this
in training it was a little bit here and
there might even crack a smile at the
end of the competition but at the moment
she has a game face on she spit too
close to the diving board though sorry
for the change in tonality I've seen too
many divers a little bit too close Oh
anyway she's a safe she's safely by the
diving board drills the entry and the
judges all award highly for that I'm
sure they do
no often heard on worldwide television
but Leon Taylor's Tarzan impression is
it's quite nicely I think
just a little whimper don't worry about
me seventy eight point four zero for
Colton over who goes into third place
but is so so tight at the top of
Malaysia in with three and a half three
point two yeah well that's what this
young lady can do I had it down as a
medal chance and she's faltered on a few
of the rounds left herself too much to
do but that is bang on the money this
inward three and a half superb height
he's a little bit close to the diving
board as well those of you that are
tweeting saying how come the divers are
so close well I agree with you they are
a little bit too close but if you move
too far away from the diving board
you'll never make this amount of
rotation so it's a fine line between
being close enough to make it and far
enough away
for safety she's back in the mix 81.6
she's only four points behind in effect
second place mmm but here come the two
Australians have been impressive and I'm
looking to get silver and bronze to kind
of turn around the Australians weak in
the Aquatic Centre in with three and a
half somersaults with tuck for Melissa
whoo well she's got it right on her
hands right on her head as we say in
diving which is actually a good thing so
up like just throwing up a little bit of
splash swallowed a bit of water the
heavy she went in looks like aerial work
is great touch shape is superb all bang
on the money just looking out shooting
up the water so maybe she'll get some
eights
if she was clean as in no splash she
would have got eight point five s and 9s
has two changes she's not quite lockout
on the finish maybe the water just the
boom what mark she got for that how much
the helper how much did it hinder her
seventy five point two zero four eight
and a seven point five and Melissa woo
and she slips a couple of places and is
back in sixth now Ken here Australian
colleague react more favorably more
positively with a back three and a half
three point three for Broman currently
in second place
sixes we'll keep her there oh I think
it's gonna get sixes or she she will
look back on that and think uh-oh
I think that's the dive that could have
potentially cost me a certain Olympic
medal still to play for if she does get
sixes which I think she will that's
going to put her very much bunched up in
this fight for the silver and bronze
what a shame Bobby could have
capitalized her if she'd had nailed that
she would have pretty much guaranteed
herself a medal now she's gonna have to
fight like crazy in the last round five
point five six and six workouts times
the degree of difficulty fifty seven
point seven five you will not believe
the scoreboard at the end of this round
just wait and see
it is absolutely astonishing how tight
it is
Megan been Fito one-and-only of course
armstand
and he done once in the competition and
this is the big one 3.30 she just get
this right she then jumps back into that
pack but she needs to be at the top of
the game eight point five so we'll put
her into first place and that certainly
won't get eight point five it's a shame
because the aerial work and the take-off
was good she was just out a little bit
early of the spin she's throwing the
water away there frustrated annoyed she
knows that her Olympic dreams of an
individual medallist slipping away just
as she slips short into the water that
she might get some sevens but she would
have needed eight and a half sand nines
to bring her back into that sandwich
that is around the second to seventh I
would call it a smorgasbord actually on
a sandwich
it is ridiculous how tight it is with
the exception of course of one diver who
is in a different competition in a
league of her own and already with
almost a 30 point lead after three
rounds almost up to 260 points already
general in back three and a half yeah
it's very good it's marginally short of
vertical it's a splash the Sentry she
goes in she really is a cut above
everyone else in this field it's a one
horse race out here today and this is
the horse we're looking at here as she
drills into the water it's probably not
going to get in the 80s but this would
be the first dive of hers that doesn't
and won't be far away
just a little marginally short here the
marks seventy nine point two zero her
lowest mark of the evening but in the
80s all the way through slips into the
70s but marginally but her lead is 49
points now look at this look at this -
86 to 85 to 84 - 84 to 82
holy moly there is nothing to pick
between
second to sixth let's see where 7th is 1
700 she's on to 82 to 82 as well to 81
to 78 so that is second to 9th all in
contention Wow it doesn't get any closer
than that thank you girls because you
have just brought this competition alive
a shoddy prelim shoddy semi and a
super-tight the last round into the
final where will the medals go one two
that young lady yeah nobody can't afford
a slip-up here 2 to 9 separated by
virtually nothing at all to everybody in
the first half of the groupings up for a
medal including for a got Chuck oh she
doesn't want a medal
she is decided with the last dive that
she does not want a medal she's feeling
the pressure maybe she looked at the
scoreboard maybe she didn't we will not
know Ariel work is good you'll see a lot
of the girls do this one to finish one
and a half twist two and a half
somersaults
way over into the water now after some
fabulous diving she's gone and let it
all go on this final dive she will play
that over and over in her head well the
door was just swung open look the
teammates say it all head in the hand
stuff ouch here's a mark
oh no 57.6 0 dear dear dear she was
right on top of the game and dive number
4 and right off her game in dive number
5 so that could well be forgot Chuck
gone in terms of metal now
this lady was the bronze medal winner
last year at the world so she knows how
to do it in the moment she is in third
place 3.2 to finish off her program
there's back two and a half samasource
1/2 2 has been done by most of the
divers in the final round round five oh
well it's okay now it needed to be
better than that to guarantee a medal it
could end up being good enough but she
really is off a game exactly the same
dive as we saw from the Ukrainian and
the Mexican they're not managing to
capsize her door was open I think she's
gonna get above she being the lead
currently only second diver in not good
enough for a medal I don't think though
wait and see 70 point four zero is the
mark
actually what over Rios does yet of
course but seven point five and a seven
she would have hope for a great deal
better than that I see in the fur
program
it's a hug from the coach and now just
has to sit and wait and see if that's
good enough it may not be she isn't
number one position right now all the
main protagonists around her are still
to go including this rather surprised
potential medalist in the only bat cake
from Italy reversed two and a half
slight difference to everybody else in
the spiralizer only two point seven
thousand got to be absolutely faultless
well it's very good it is very good but
two point seven she's finished on one of
it her lowest degree of difficulty I
think she came with tactics not very
well played it's obviously a favorite
dive that's why she finishes on it but
she can't match the three point twos Wow
but it's a good effort 88.5 I don't
think that will be good enough to get
above Espinosa
and chin to the water well this phone
around the scoreboard just kind of
grinds to a halt doesn't it let's say
waiting here they come and it isn't good
enough to overtake the Mexican into
second place and sadly from her point of
view and I think the look on her face
will indicate exactly what she's
thinking at sixty seven point five zero
three fifty point oh five means the best
she can realistically do now is a bronze
and hope that everybody else falters and
the rest of the program not likely to
happen who you damn oh she did perfect
tens she would get into a middle
position but always she'd been diving
today Wow
so that's going to get a bag full of
nines maybe even a nine point five so
who you Dan is decided to wake up and do
too near on perfect dives in mine for
she scored the highest score dive of the
competition at 89 this is probably going
to be the second high-scoring dive of
the competition she's just shown two
bursts of brilliance and because of the
quality of the competition so far and
they hated missed nature she's probably
put herself back not too far not too far
away from the podium be very interesting
to see well he kinda marks all three
four nine just behind back team yeah she
is and just behind Sanchez which means
in effect you will not begin here middle
today I guess the kampachi and her
fellow Chinese general in and it's got
so much to actually secure the gold
already just has to complete the dive in
any fashion and she'll be okay Rosalie
and filly on again
not gonna be in the medals today back
two and a half somersaults one half
twist Pike three point two to finish
yeah she asked a little bit over a
fraction over she goes in he's had a
tough day but she did get better and
better as we move from the premiums to
the semies to the final young lady
obviously already Olympic bronze
medalist with Megan who's coming up
later on as you know this year's final
dive in the competition it's so tight
you never really know do you don't know
she doesn't know her marks yet so make
you a wait a little bit before yeah we
have two divers who and for the on three
four nine we have Becky on 350 at out
ideas for the medals but Sanchez has a
six-point advantage she currently is in
what in effect is the silver medal
position for the Mexican there she is
waiting and hoping and knowing that
she's been diving better tonight and she
did in the prelims and in the semi final
as well
yep just get a fish off her program with
the dive that many did in the first
round
it's that forward three and a half
somersaults with Pike to finish for the
German well what if it would have died
to finish on as well what a finish to
the dive to buried the entry hardly a
ripple of splash again this wow it's so
so close she was tenth wasn't she after
the fourth eye and I think with a lower
degree of difficulty even though it's
been performed exceptionally well it's
that standing dive to finish on well
probably gonna be a bit too much to
stand on the podium or is it
78 78 from bone time eight point five
and nine she's gone into second place
351 no game bad key out of a medal and
the German you know we thought was gone
for all money may not quite be yet
there's still some divers more highly
ranked in terms of the standings and
chic including yulia coulton over it's a
three point two like many of the others
are back two and a half somersaults 1/2
twists to 84 her current score 8 in the
70s well I think that is going to go
into the 70s this spot Yulia responding
to the pressure knows it's so tight
there's nothing she can do apart from
concentrate on the dive at hand and she
has done a very good job marginally
short she's gone in but she's clean tidy
and she was in fifth place before so I
think she's gonna top it that is good
enough let's wait and see some agonizing
wait come on
scoreboard where are you picked in yet
so devious Smith it's okay 7300 on its
top place she's overtaken Espinoza
Sanchez by one point seven points now
it's not going to be gold fir but at the
moment
Colton over is looking at a silver medal
Espinoza Sanchez is looking at a bronze
but there's still some more to come
including handle a pang same dive same
kind of mark needed 75 or there abouts
might just get it done for her oh it's a
good effort just marginally over
vertical or they could have shout and
cheer as loud as they come because they
know there are teammates know how tight
it is Wow what if climax
well if planned alone it was just a
little bit more vertical desi just
tipping over it's a shame it's a 3.2
again all the girls using this time to
finish on oh she made some mistakes
earlier in a program otherwise she'd
have been guaranteed a medal look at
this look at this
Wow there you go three five nine she's
going to the lead Dalton over down to
two Espinoza Sanchez will not get a
medal today
goodness gracious me what drama seventy
six point eight zero for the nineteen
year old from Malaysia so we do a
calculation not guaranteed a medal yet
though just not yeah Melissa Roos in
contention of course she's a serving
contention well she still is still tight
if she nails this it's gotta be around
eighty though yep on this three point
two back two and a half seven sauce 1/2
twist she's looking at the big eight
zero to get up in the middles oh it's
probably not clean enough a little bit
too much splashy is that bike there you
see the other contenders they've done
their dives now they have to wait and
see what the judges think
Melissa rude giving it all on this last
dive a little bit too far away from the
diving board but she does get in it's
tidy a little bit too much splash where
will she finish that's my client agent
their boyfriend their marks coming very
soon she can't wait we can't wait Oh
three five eight just behind the
Malaysian yeah she's into second place
currently she might finger LeBrons were
there again she might be edged out of it
by her teammate Brittany broman sixteen
years of age and she needs well not as
much to go into the lead she needs 76
this was my bet for the medal 76 is all
she needs say all she needs still got to
be executed this dive pretty accurately
three point two back two and a half
somersaults one artist look for 76 or
above to go into the lead
yes that's good enough that will be
silver for the 16 year old Australian
what an incredible contest yes that is
good enough that is good enough Wow
outstanding performance wow it's not
often I look into my crystal ball and
predict something so accurately but they
did say after the prelims in the semi
but this young 16 year old is on for a
medal and that is the silver right there
well done well done Britney big smile
big mark she's praying he regards aya oh
yes
eighty one point six zero but Brittany
Broman Australian silver it's this one
than beside her name but there's a
Chinese who is far far away in terms of
competition and she is not gonna catch
her but while she has just captured is a
silver medal and it will be the way
things are looking
Australian silver and Malaysian bronze
Pam what a competition and that means
that Melissa woo misses out by just over
one point from a middle a clip in
Australian to three Megan benefit Oh to
finish off with for Canada back two and
a half again one of the half twists
she's finished so strongly and she'll be
kicking herself because of a few dives
where she's been under par she didn't
quite leave herself in contention for
this well this final flourish that we've
been seeing here in the final round all
the girls choosing to do this most of
them the back two and a half one and a
half twist all finishing on the
three-point to died for dive for dive
for dive direct comparison some divers
choosing to dive from the left hand or
the right hand side of the board or the
middle it's complete preference and here
we go that agonizing wait now my
computer has a bit of a sense of humor
just once everybody hold on for a little
longer and tenth place is where she will
finish certainly not where she wanted to
finish and she's distraught by that
thought she could do better
as expected to do better but just
now let's round off with something of
real class real finesse and real
expertise never troubled never Ries
Tepig online always impeccable today
it's been a master class of 10 metre
platform diving from general in three
and a half to finish now it's a dive
back two and a half one and a half twist
absolutely phenomenal performance from
prelim to semi to final retaining her
Olympic title that she won when she was
only 15 years old in Beijing here she is
at 19 and she is stormed to another
victory she was the only diver here
really in this competition it was a
one-horse race she left everyone from
dive one and this finishing off in fine
style indeed showing her class there was
a real fight for the lesser medals and
chain rule in goes into diving history
retaining her Olympic title what a dive
from this young lady and what a set of
dives 86 to finish eighty six point four
zero she wins the competition by 56
points 56 points between first place and
second place and that is quite
astonishing and quite astonishing too
for that 16 year old from Australia who
really cannot believe it it's true pinch
yourself because it is 360 6.50 and
she's going to go to friends and family
and hug and kiss and it'll be just such
an emotional moment for her who's she
trying to pick out the Australians are
over that side she doesn't know what to
do
where to go who to hard cooter talk to
16 years of age a great semi and a
fantastic final for Broman of Australia
and let's not overlook that lady and
Ryan's medalist for Hamed thought a
one-stage she might have blown it she
had to do a lot of work at the end this
is how I finished them for two 2.30 for
Chen Groban winning her silver by 7 but
the bronze only secured by Angela pang
by 1.1 mark and everybody else below
that line will go I've only had done
that we've only had done that who you
Dan did well to move up tonight
Elia forgot Chuck on the basis of her
opening dive in the last round falling
right down to the bottom and the two
Canadians in 10th and 11th well that was
absolutely anybody's for the silver and
bronze Wow
how I've not seen a competition that
tight with the remainder of the pack
Jeremy Lin way out in front and everyone
else well how in the mix I didn't think
anyone wanted it at one stage but this
young lady certainly did Britney Probert
16 years old Panda Lenna 19 in the
Olympic champion generally in 19 so it's
won by girls under the age of 19 top
three and well it's great about this she
really didn't know what to do where do I
go who do I talk to
what's a protocol now can I go and see
my family can I go and say hello to my
friends or is there a medal so she
really didn't know it's like a head was
spinning as she took in the realization
that she's an Olympic silver medalist
yeah I know what that feelings like you
have to keep calm composed focused when
you're performing under such expectation
and pressure and when you actually do it
when you look at that scoreboard and
your name is next to a medal position
it's like the the dam burst and all
those emotions just flood come flooding
through and you don't know which ways up
or down or sideways look at that great
embrace with a coach
and there we are Britney with her coat
such a journey the hours and hours of
hard work and dedication payoff embraces
all round well and then of course the
fourth fifth and sixth and seventh will
be in eighth the ninth and tenth and
eleventh and twelfth and this
competition will be thinking what if
what if I was just a bit better on one
of my dives maybe just maybe it would
have been my moment my moment to stand
on that podium but today Chen was way
out in front
roben well I backed a silver medalist
and panned Elena pang fantastic in
bronze whoo just outside
well agonizing fourth place now if you
are a diver or a swimmer who has to get
up at a ridiculously early hour of the
morning we know you do four o'clock five
o'clock in the morning to go to training
this young lady who's just won the
silver medal gets up at 4:15 every
morning for training she has to go well
over an hour to go to Brisbane to the
Gold Coast to Train and obviously over
an hour back she's still at school
trying to combine all that and just see
the reward it has brought to her by just
digging in there and going to you know
what 4:15 the one that really won't be
getting out of bed but this one I want
to achieve and she has achieved she's
not achieved it as a fluke you may think
because some of the bigger names failed
a bit today or was slightly off their
game no she didn't win it by default she
won it on their own efforts they're just
fantastic I was must admit I was
disappointed through the prelims through
the semi-final how that final turned out
to be a real corker and as we wait for
the moment when the medals are handed
I'd just get chance to reflect on the
thrills we've had here in the diving
pool obviously the Olympic Games started
on the 27th the diving first contest on
the 29th that we've been here every
single day part from one we have left we
haven't left yeah I've just I think I
just stay here I stay here with my
headphones on waiting for more action
and yep so that was a slow slow burn up
the women's platform
what a exciting climax I can't ask for
more than that more drama on the last
round there bub you're our calculators
and our you know predictions and crystal
balls and Wow top eight all over 350 top
eight all over 350 the bronze 366 the
Silverado 366 the bronze 359 and right
down to backe who again looked like she
might be in there but what did for her
and we keep making this point she had a
low tariff dive to finish right at the
end now she'd had a 3.1 a 3.2 or she had
gone for a broker then we might be
talking about the Italian as a bronze
medalist possibly a silver medal but she
went for an easy option and easy her
options shall we say in the last round
an ultimate whenever Rios is doing 3.2 s
and you're doing a 2.9 there's a big
differential there yeah that's why it's
2.7 actually the dice she finished on
she's giving away point 5 she of course
used her three-point to the back two and
a half one and a half twist which you
saw all the ladies doing the final round
notice the game of tactics that probably
didn't work out for Naomi bhakti they're
from Italy finishing in eighth when she
was very much in there for a medal what
am I the Canadians disappointing
yeah disappointing for the girls there
but of course they do have an Olympic
medal in their room in the Olympic
Village or wherever they choose to keep
it from the synchronized event and they
dived Wow awesomely well in that event a
highly run contest as you would imagine
and they ended up with an Olympic bronze
and couldn't quite raise their game here
in the final or all ladies faltering but
some more than others and the Canadians
just finishing at the bottom of the pack
just look at the sequence of dies for
Chen 85 84 86 slightly less slightly
being the operative word
seventy nine point two at 86 what a
sequence of dives ocean everyone to the
nineties and she never had a 10 sadly
which i think would have underlined that
performance but you know how consistent
is that well that's the name of the game
isn't it and she is you know a cut above
the rest if you just look at that lowest
scoring dive of 79 and then everything
in the 80s and with the degree of
difficult
she's using she's maxing out isn't she
so nines pretty much across the board on
most of her dies makes her untouchable
what an absolute champion to retain her
Olympic title and she's only 19 how can
you have two Olympic titles when you're
19 Wow
and one of that bourbon who dropped will
not drop but silly was well below what
should be around before opening dive was
weak for her low degree of difficulty 60
that could have been more and dive
number four which was her what was it
about three and a half that was the one
that was the big dive probably her bogey
dive and she did underperformed
certainly on that dive but it didn't
affect the result look at that she was
clearly in bronze by six points yeah
only four bonds I mean a silver a head
of bronze by six points my massive
margin but it was what she needed and
well that's kind of the final we needed
because I think we often a bit
lackluster a bit lukewarm after the
prelims last night 75 didn't really get
us out of our seats and on the edge of
them this morning but just because it
was so competitive and so close Yuri
didn't know which way was gonna go you
knew the gold pretty much from the
outset there's never gonna be much
question about that but it's really
exciting when you sing to countries or
in this case five or six countries all
going for the bronze and silver medals
yeah it doesn't get it's like the
swimming mates all coming in in a line
you never really know where who's gonna
get it until the touch but obviously the
drama here in the diving pool because it
is like for like dive for dive most of
the girls then opting to you know decide
but an hour before the competition the
dives need to be submitted to the
officials and so we know what's coming
up there's the game of tactics and where
some of them very well played so if you
have just joined us just a recount we'll
have the medal ceremony for you very
shortly but chain rule in of China 19
years of age has retained her title from
Beijing the world champion from last
year in Shanghai in great style she won
it by 56 points in the end all very
nearly give or take a couple of sented
points roben of australia britney broman
16 years of age the big surprise
although actually after the semi is not
quite so surprised we kind of almost
marked jacquard on her doing role
tonight winning her silver medal by
seven points and handling a pang but one
stage we thought hard just giving
herself a bit too much to do is 64 and
dive number three and she seemed to have
let it slip but then she came back with
an 81 and a 76 and pulled herself right
up the standings a minister whoo not
gonna be her day by just over a point
one point one zero in the end cult anova
had it in her hands and just couldn't I
mean she was consistent throughout but
just didn't have that big dive in the
80's to lift her up there Espinoza
Sanchez was not quite fortunate to make
the semis anyway improved in the
semi-final and certainly improved in the
final as well but again wasn't quite
enough for the other Christians sure
well a shoe might be a very surprising
medalist in one stage but everybody else
up their game and backe in 8th place
right at the bottom every case you're
wondering we already heard about one
Chinese who you Dan just never got going
early on and all the sudden from out of
absolutely nowhere to immaculate dives
and we just didn't see that coming no
great word well we've seen it in
training she was world silver medalist
last year in Shanghai in a performance
there was outstanding she in fact pushed
Chen so where if you remember that
contest it was very closely run and
since we've seen it here in prelims and
semies who you done it's been way off
the pace first three rounds here she was
way off the pace and then she comes out
with the highest-scoring dive of the
competition at 89 points for about three
and a half which is three point three
degree of difficulty and then she backs
it right up with her back two and a half
one and a half twist for 86.4 and then
she puts herself right back up in
contention and ends up in fifth position
well she missed out on the middle by two
point well two points 349 against 351 so
that's how close it was
so no you ended up in Knights I beg your
pardon but she went all the way up there
Yeah right we are ready to go the divers
in position to be paraded on poolside
it shows a lot of tears and a lot of
emotion and a lot of excitement now
they're probably not for the victor cuz
she's done it so many times before it's
pretty much routine at the chain rule in
but for the others from AB roben first
time for Pam who was involved in the
synchro last week so she got a flavor of
this building and the competition in the
pool in the synchronized event last week
she has picked up a bronze medal but
that's a lineup we weren't really
expecting when the competition got
underway it is another goal for China
they've only missed out so far on the
men's three meter individual all the
other goals have gone to China there's a
nice bonus bronze for and he's delighted
and I think Chan will break open a smile
shortly and they will definitely see one
from Brittney browbone who it's just
taking it all in
looking around and looking at the crowd
and wanting to soak up every little
fiber and what is happening here to hurt
probably in reality we'll go to bed
tonight say I'll wake up I will have
been dreaming but you haven't it's true
it's real and it's happening right now
to the 16 year old from Australia
becomes a presentation party
which is
let
because the medal ceremony and the medal
presentations first of all to the 19
year old from Malaysia and develop and
350 9.20 the marks for the Malaysian and
she's absolutely thrilled to get that
bronze yeah enjoy it make the most of it
it's a hard-fought competition and some
big names fell by the wayside here not
she
big metals are they oh you see tears oh
yes here smile what are we gonna see
from Brittany broman yes a big smile
[Applause]
looks to the sizable Australian
contingent looks towards her teammates
that chunky bit of metalworkers much
they still will wear of course it is a
silver medal
so it's silverware in those terms and
they're delighted
waterworks you in the start amongst the
family and friends though you know she
can keep it together
but another absolutely impeccable day at
the office this is what she calls her
office general in and the Chinese tend
to do this they go and littleroot march
around the metal platform taking the
hands of the two bronze and silver
medalists and first real emotional
reaction from general in this is a
chunky bit of metalwork around her neck
she receives a bouquet of flowers and
their big champion 2008 and a big
champion 2012 she's down again and world
champion as well
the unbeatable icing san-chan ruling
with gold for China in the women's 10
metre platform final and once again the
national anthem of China will ring out
around the Aquatic Center
[Music]
large proportion of the Aquatic Center
crowd have stayed behind to acknowledge
a thrilling competition certainly for
the silver and the bronze and the
imperious gold medalist who is Chen
ruling so the women have done their
stuff in 23 hours or less it'll be the
men's turn men's 10-meter platform final
more entrance to that than we will have
any competition here in the diving pool
Leon Taylor of course competed at in a
picks in 2000 and 2004 in that events
and 1996 you know what everyone wait you
sound too old I'm just going to mention
the ones that were people can remember
whichever color television here what are
you thinking what are you hoping what
what are you expecting well it's a
marathon
32 boys going head-to-head cut to 18 and
they've got to get up early the next
morning we've seen this program and it's
tough because the men's final is
actually going to be a little bit later
on Saturday night 8:30 p.m. local time
so it's who can hold their body together
who can hold their nerve and who can
dive most consistently because I would
dare to say the level is going to be
through the roof I need to save my voice
I need to save my energy and I cannot
wait to bring the blue ribbon event to
you some amazing dives ahead still to
finish off and I would like to predict
lots and lots of perfect scores coming
maybe not so much in the plenaries but
semi-final and final I'm pretty sure the
judges will be inputting at least one or
two perfect ends and maybe even more
than that worth tuning in for wherever
you are in the world please come and
join us
alright so check your times for Friday
evening it will be UK time at 1900 BST
the preliminaries for the men's
then the semi-final will be on Saturday
morning local time at 10 o'clock
RCS all at your London reference points
in terms of your time differential
because you do not want to be missing
the prelims on Friday the semi fans
certainly the final on Saturday night at
7:30 local time thank you for joining us
for the women's 10 metre platform we
lived up to all the expectations and a
few surprises along the way not with the
winner but with the silver and the
bronze medal from Leon Taylor myself Bob
Bala thank you for joining us at the
Aquatic Center we'll go back to the
final event of the diving competition in
about 23 hours from now till then
goodbye
[Music]
you